<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
  <title>Sparetime Bluegrass</title>
  <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass</link>
  <description>We're having a good time...</description>
  <language>en-us</language>
  <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 18:03:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
  <atom:link href="https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/assets/rss/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Goodbye Old Friend</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=goodbye-old-friend</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=goodbye-old-friend</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/jim.jpg" alt="image" /></p>
<p>It is with sorrow in my heart that I tell you that our banjo player, Jim Robarts, has passed. The last 2 years he has battled the re-occurence of his Vietnam War related cancer. This year we completed a new CD and he played gigs through the summer. He Passed peacefully in hospice 10/26/23. His smile and 5 string playing will remain in our memories for years to come. Goodbye old friend. BB</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>So where did a year go?</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=so-where-did-a-year-go</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=so-where-did-a-year-go</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>It seems a year has past with nothing happening. Actually much has happened. Lisa became a full time educator with 3 kids home and the schools closed, Jim became a great grandparent and Dale learned the accordion (well no, but he told me he did nothing), &amp; Me and Lorie played music on the front porch.</p>
<p><img src="assets/images/PorchConcert-500x337.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Bob Batyko and his wife, Lori Docken, right, who normally play in a bluegrass band, perform two songs, including "You Can Have Her" and "Wheels on the Bus," during a weekly concert for their neighbors from their front porch on the Near East Side in Madison, Wis., Wednesday, March 24, 2021. AMBER ARNOLD, STATE JOURNAL</p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Thanks Tom Gresser</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=thanks-tom-gresser</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=thanks-tom-gresser</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/IMG_2935-500x375.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>We did a Sunday afternoon with Bill &amp; Bobbie Malone to raise some money for the late great Roxbury Tavern. Thanks to Tom for all the great shows he sponsored. Hopefully the next "new" owners will bring back the life the Tavern once had. Thanks to all who came out.</p>
<p><img src="assets/images/IMG_2936-e1580498839643-500x375.jpg" alt="" /></p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Come on 2020</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=come-on-2020</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=come-on-2020</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/ST-NYE-2019-500x312.jpg" alt="" /> <img src="assets/images/ST-at-NYE-2019-selfie-500x500.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>We had a great time at the Geezers New Year's Eve PARTY.</p>
<p>A Sold Out event. Many of our musical buddies are in the house.</p>
<p>We did a folky sing-a-long tune to remind everybody we are all in this together. &nbsp;And told everyone again to go out and vote.</p>
<p>And Eleanor stole the show! Thanks to Common Ground and everyone who came on out.</p>
<p>Now in January we have a fund raiser for the Roxbury Tavern Alumni. &nbsp;Seems the buyer skipped out without paying some of the bills &amp; we are helping cover these costs. &nbsp;&nbsp;In the mean time the Roxbury Tavern is for sale…. &nbsp;We are looking for the right person to take this place over and make it our home again. &nbsp;Hey Gina, Trent, Stacy… you know who you are and this is the spot to return to the gastro/musical spot it was. &nbsp;We need someone to step up.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Calling all GEEZERS</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=calling-all-geezers</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=calling-all-geezers</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/Geezers-New-Years-Flyer-2020-386x500.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>It's time to ring in the new year with SpareTime Bluegrass at the Common Ground in Middleton. Join us and our Roxbury regulars as we kick out 2019 and welcome in the 2020 Presidential election year. So this time next year we'll tell you what we really think. But join us on Dec 31 from 7 to 9. see flyer for details</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Winter 2019</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=winter-2019</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=winter-2019</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/ST-at-Faded-Roots-Dec-2019-500x375.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>We are kicking this old year out.</p>
<p>We started December at Faded Roots in Sun Prairie. It was Ladies night and Jen got up and sang some tunes with us. Thanks Jen.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Fall 2019</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=fall-2019</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=fall-2019</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/ST-at-rox-reunion-10_19-500x281.jpg" alt="" /> <img src="assets/images/Rox-Tavern-Reunion-10_2019-500x281.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>Well hello,</p>
<p>Here we are wrapped up in fall with much cooler weather. SpareTime had fewer summer time gigs this year but made up for it with a full schedule in Sept/Oct from Sun Prairie to Lake Mills to Middleton and Madison.</p>
<p>And what a gathering we had with the Roxbury Tavern Reunion.</p>
<p>We are singing the Buck Owens tune "Hello Trouble". Just take one good look at that group and "here comes trouble that I'm never gonna see since you been away" Thanks to Tom and all the Roxburians.</p>
<p>Great to see everyone and we are announcing that The Geezers New Years Eve party will be at the Common Ground this year. keep an eye here and we'll let you know when tickets are on sale.</p>
<p>Hope to see you soon.</p>
<p>BB</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Geezer's New Years has a new location! - Common Ground in Middleton!</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=geezers-new-years-has-a-new-location-common-ground-in-middleton</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=geezers-new-years-has-a-new-location-common-ground-in-middleton</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/Screen-Shot-2018-11-26-at-11.11.25-PM-388x500.png" alt="" /></p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>This weekend!</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=this-weekend</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=this-weekend</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>We are BUSY this weekend.&nbsp; We'd love to see you at one of these venues:</p>
<ul>
<li>Saturday, Aug 25, 5-6:30pm - Beer Jolais at Angell Park in Sun Prairie</li>
<li>Sunday, Aug 26, 2-4pm - The Last Hurrah at Roxbury Tavern in Roxbury</li>
<li>Sunday, Aug 26, 5-7pm - Devil's Lake in Baraboo</li>
</ul>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Dreaming of summer...</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=dreaming-of-summer</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=dreaming-of-summer</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>We're slowly starting to book summer gigs…mark your calendars!</p>
<ul>
<li>Saturday, <strong>June 23</strong>, 6-9pm, Tyranena Brewery (1025 Owen St, Lake Mills)</li>
<li>Thursday, <strong>July 5</strong>, 5-7pm, UW Union Terrace (800 Langdon St, Madison)</li>
</ul>
<p>Meanwhile, come celebrate St. Patrick's Day with us at Roxbury Tavern and try some of their delectable Irish stew!</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Come on out for an afternoon of music and fun!</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sunday-february-11-come-on-out-for-an-afternoon-of-music-and-fun</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sunday-february-11-come-on-out-for-an-afternoon-of-music-and-fun</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/UnitedWay2018-325x500.jpg" alt="" /></p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>SpareTime Large Band with Scott on Dobro and Paul on fiddle</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-large-band</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-large-band</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/Geezers-351x500.jpg" alt="" /></p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Come hear some music and stories about bluegrass...</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=come-hear-some-music-and-stories-about-bluegrass</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=come-hear-some-music-and-stories-about-bluegrass</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/VeronaLibrary-386x500.jpeg" alt="" /></p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>July gig at the UW Union Terrace</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=july-gig-at-the-uw-union-terrace</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=july-gig-at-the-uw-union-terrace</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>How lucky are we to play with a backdrop like this?!</p>
<p><img src="assets/images/170706-Sparetime-at-Terrace-500x375.jpeg" alt="" /></p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>2017 United Way Fundraiser Was a Success!</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=2017-united-way-fundraiser-was-a-success</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=2017-united-way-fundraiser-was-a-success</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/2017UnitedWayPhoto.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>The 2017 United Way Bluegrass Fundraiser had the largest audience yet!&nbsp; Thanks to all of the bands and The Barrymore for hosting such a great event.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>United Way Bluegrass Benefit</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=united-way-bluegrass-benefit</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=united-way-bluegrass-benefit</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/UnitedWay2017-663x1024.png" alt="image" /></p>
<p><strong>ALTERNATIVE FACTS FROM SPARETIME</strong></p>
<p>Life has been wonderful for the multinational conglomerate that is The Sparetime Bluegrass Band. We’ve been breaking records wherever we’ve played. The CDs have all gone platinum (we gold plate everything in our lives), and we only play the best instruments……We’re serious.</p>
<p>On Sunday February 12th we will be taking part in United Way Bluegrass Benefit at the Barrymore Theater in Madison. We were, of course, the first band to do it way back when. We were actually the only band at the first one. The audience at that first one was enormous…you probably remember newspaper stories about gridlock after the event.</p>
<p>This year the crowd estimate is about 80,000 to 100,000, making it the largest benefit concert anywhere in the Mid-West. We’re happy, in our own large way, to be a part of this.
&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>THE OTHER FACTS</strong></p>
<p>Actually there is a benefit concert at the Barrymore on February 12. We are a part of it. We did do the first one and were the only band. We are always proud to be a part of the concert. The event is a wonderful family friendly concert. It gives the kids a chance to see Dave Landau in concert and a chance for everyone to see strong local bluegrass musicians get together to assist the United Way.</p>
<p>The doors open at Noon and events run until about 6:00 p.m. We would love to have you all there.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Kids dancing on the Terrace</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=kids-dancing-on-the-terrace</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=kids-dancing-on-the-terrace</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/IMG_8776.jpg" alt="image" /> On June 9th SpareTime played the newly reopened Memorial Union Terrace. The weather was great, as were the sound people from the Union. There is nothing like playing on a stage, the backdrop of which, is Lake Mendota. The Terrace has been redone and better than ever. Also present were a number of children who seemed to be dancing the afternoon away.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>James King</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=james-king</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=james-king</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>SpareTime is saddened by the news of the passing of James King at 57. He was a friend of ours for over fifteen years and we opened for him at the Copper Grid and Dudley’s. We were on the bill at Swamp n’ Grass and helped get his unique voice into a concert at the Roxbury Tavern.</p>
<p>James was called The Bluegrass Storyteller and excelled at poignant songs fraught with emotion and conviction. He was one of the most honest artists in traditional bluegrass---often moved to tears on stage by the lyrics he sang. One particular musical moment that comes to mind occurred at the Copper Grid when James, with only his guitar, sang “Dream of the Miner’s Child”. He imbued that hoary chestnut with utter sincerity and conviction. There were few dry eyes.</p>
<p>With James, what you saw was what you got (warts and all). And there were warts. At various times he lived hard. The road took a toll. He was in declining health for over a year.</p>
<p>Our thoughts go out to his loved ones.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Sparetime Goes To Schumacher Farm</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-goes-to-schumacher-farm</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-goes-to-schumacher-farm</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Schumacher Farm, just east of Waunakee, held Spring Bluegrass, its first bluegrass festival on May 14th. Truman’s Ridge, Northern Comfort, Milkhouse Radio, Kristy Larson's Honky Tonk Trio, RF Kieffer, Down from the Hills, Soggy Prairie Boys, and SpareTime were on the bill.</p>
<p>We had a great time despite the exceedingly cold weather. The audience was warm and inviting, and the adaptability of all the groups to the conditions was marvelous. SpareTime has high hopes for the continuing festival. It’s in a great location, with fine facilities. We really need something like this in the area and want next year to be better than ever.</p>
<p>The next few weeks for SpareTime are filled with good events. We play Whole Foods on June 2nd, and journey to Tyranena Brewery in Lake Mills on Friday, June 3rd. This is always a good time. We get to see fans farther east from Madison and play outdoors in a relaxed garden setting. On June 9th we will be outside at the UW Memorial Union Terrace. They have been building on the Terrace, improving the stage and completing other structural additions. It just reopened and we are looking forward to a warm Spring evening with our backs to Lake Monona.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Summer is coming...</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=summer-is-coming</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=summer-is-coming</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>We are currently working on our spring and summer schedules.&nbsp; Check back for updates, but this is what we've got so far.&nbsp; We'd love to see you!</p>
<ul>
<li>Sunday, <strong>April 10</strong>, 4-5pm, Harmony Bar (2201 Atwood Ave, Madison)</li>
<li>Sunday, <strong>April 24</strong>, 4:30-5:30pm, BOS Meadery "Bees of Spring Bluegrass Festival" (Check out the full festival from 12-6pm) (849 E. Washington Ave, Madison) <a href="http://www.bosmeadery.com/events/event/1st-annual-bees-of-spring-bluegrass-festival/">http://www.bosmeadery.com/events/event/1st-annual-bees-of-spring-bluegrass-festival/</a></li>
<li>Saturday, <strong>May 14</strong>, 1:20-2:20pm, Schumacher Farm Park "Spring Bluegrass" (Check out the full festival from 12-6pm) (5682 Highway 19 at Schumacher Rd, Waunakee) <a href="http://www.schumacherfarmpark.org/event-2223378">http://www.schumacherfarmpark.org/event-2223378</a></li>
<li>Saturday, <strong>May 28</strong>, private event</li>
<li>Thursday, <strong>June 2</strong>, 5-7pm, Whole Foods "Burgers and Bluegrass" (3313 University Ave, Madison)</li>
<li>Friday, <strong>June 3</strong>, 6-9pm, Tyranena Brewery (1025 Owen St, Lake Mills)</li>
<li>Thursday, <strong>June 9</strong>, 5-7pm, UW Union Terrace (800 Langdon St, Madison)</li>
<li>Sunday, <strong>June 19</strong>, 4-6pm, Father's Day at Roxbury Tavern (8901 County Rd Y, Roxbury)</li>
<li>Thursday, <strong>July 21</strong>, 11:30am-1pm, Out to Lunch (Iron Mountain, MI)</li>
<li>Thursday, <strong>July 28</strong>, 5-7pm, Whole Foods "Burgers and Bluegrass" (3313 University Ave, Madison)</li>
<li>Thursday, <strong>September 15</strong>, 6-8pm, High Noon Patio (701 E. Washington Ave, Madison)</li>
</ul>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>The days are getting longer</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=the-days-are-getting-longer</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=the-days-are-getting-longer</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>SpareTime is busy booking for Spring and Summer. Hope to see you at the Roxbury Tavern for the St Patricks day show from 7 to 9 on March 17th. Check our Calendar for the gigs we already have booked and we will try and send out updates and Facebook posts.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Summer is here</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=summer-is-here</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=summer-is-here</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Here is the SpareTime Bluegrass 2015 Summer Schedule Stop and have a beer with us.</p>
<ul>
<li>May 30 Burgers and brews @ Capital brewery 4-5</li>
<li>June 3 Whole Foods 5-7</li>
<li>June 27 Tyranena 6-9</li>
<li>July 8 Whole Foods 7-7</li>
<li>July 22 Whole Foods 4-6</li>
<li>July 30 UW Memorial Union Terrace 5-7</li>
<li>Aug 5 Whole Foods 5-7</li>
<li>Sept 24 High Noon 6-8</li>
</ul>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>SpringTime for SpareTime</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=springtime-for-sparetime</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=springtime-for-sparetime</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>It is not yet Spring, but we can see it from here. We have some new gigs and we've been nominated for the MAMA's (Madison Area Music Awards). Please vote for us!! &nbsp;It will cost you $5 to join and vote and the money is used to get musical instruments for kids. &nbsp;Here is the link. &nbsp;&amp; a big thanks.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.broadjam.com/mama/index.php">http://www.broadjam.com/mama/index.php</a></p>
<p>Here is what we are nominated for:</p>
<p>MAMAs Song of the Year</p>
<ul>
<li>Category: Cover Song</li>
<li>You might think</li>
<li>Category: Folk/Americana</li>
<li>These Days</li>
<li>Category: Country/Bluegrass</li>
<li>Shackles and chains</li>
<li>Category: Unique</li>
<li>Riding the rapids</li>
<li>Category: Alternative</li>
<li>Vauxhall</li>
</ul>
<p>MAMAs Album of the Year</p>
<p>Vauxhall</p>
<ul>
<li>Category: Country/Bluegrass</li>
<li>Vauxhall</li>
<li>Category: Folk/American</li>
<li>Vauxhall</li>
</ul>
<p>MAMAs Artist of the Year</p>
<ul>
<li>SpareTime Bluegrass</li>
</ul>
<p>MAMAs Instrumentalist of the Year</p>
<ul>
<li>Specialty Instrument</li>
<li>Jim Robarts banjo</li>
</ul>
<p>MAMAs Vocalist of the Year</p>
<ul>
<li>Category:Female Vocalist</li>
<li>Lisa Case Doro</li>
</ul>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Vauxhall</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=vauxhall</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=vauxhall</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/vauxhall2014.jpg" alt="image" /></p>
<p>It is here. The new SpareTime CD is out. Vauxhall. Our 9th recording and 1st with fiddler/singer Lisa Case Doro is dedicated to all of the musicians who have played as members of SpareTime or been SpareParts for a gig. Thanks to Steve Gotcher at Audio for the Arts for his great recording/mixing and mastering and to Allyson Casey for the CD cover design. Thanks also to the venues we have played these 20 years of SpareTime and to the many fans who have come out and supported the music.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Fall is here</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=fall-is-here</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=fall-is-here</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Hello Fall, Summer just blew past us all. Lisa was out on Maternity Leave and now she is back. We have some shows lined up for the fall but we have been spending most of our energy on the new CD. The CD titled Vauxhall (after Jim's first car) is in final prep and will be ready for the Xmas gift-giving season. We like it and hope you will too. It is our first CD with Lisa singing and playing. Steve Gotcher from Audio for the Arts is again doing the recording and mixing. Winter is coming on and that is wood shed din' time when we learn some new tunes. Send me a note if you got a tune SpareTime ought to be doing. So come out and see us when you can. I will try and keep the calendar up to date. We look forward to a milder winter than last year and some of your faces at our gigs. Peace out BB</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Oh My, Winter...Winter...Winter and then Summer</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=oh-my-winter-winter-winter-and-then-summer</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=oh-my-winter-winter-winter-and-then-summer</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>We made it thru April and in May start playing outside gigs. Lisa is with us till mid June when she has asked for some time off. Till then we are playing all we can. So see us in the next weeks at Tyranena, Whole Foods, Capital Brewery and the Memorial Union Terrace with a mid summer appearance at the nearly historic Roxbury Tavern. Stop and have a beer or a cherry coke with the band. Cheers.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Winter 2014 - When Will It Quit???</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=winter-2014-when-will-this-winter-quit</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=winter-2014-when-will-this-winter-quit</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Cold and more cold. it must be time for some hot Bluegrass. SpareTime continues to play at the Frequency on the 3rd Thursdays of the month from 6 to 8. $5 or 3 cans of food for the WilMar foodbank.</p>
<p>We are playing for the big United Way Bluegrass Benefit at the Barrymore Theatre on Sunday Feb. 9. A full afternoon of bluegrass for $10. Please stop out to support this good cause.</p>
<p>February also brings studio time for SpareTime at Audio for the Arts. We hope to have a new CD out with Lisa singing and fiddling by this summer.</p>
<p>March brings our St Patrick's gig at the legendary Roxbury Tavern. We are playing on Sunday to give us all Monday to chase the snakes out.</p>
<p>April SpareTime is playing for the Ladies of Bluegrass 7th Annual Music Festival at Watering Hole 2017 Velp Ave, Greenbay, Wisc.</p>
<p>&amp; then comes Summer</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Where did the summer go?</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=where-did-the-summer-go</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=where-did-the-summer-go</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Here we are seeing the first of the fall weather. Thoughts of the summer gigs are still with us and thanks to all who came out. We are working on learning some new tunes, reworking some old tunes and getting back into the studio for the 1st SpareTime Bluegrass CD with Lisa. Keep an eye open for us and we'll be watching for you. See you soon.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Spring-Summer 2013</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=spring-summer-2013</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=spring-summer-2013</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Where does the time go?&nbsp; Here we are looking at the Spring and Summer gigs for SpareTime. &nbsp;They include stops at Capital Brewery, Whole Foods, The Frequency, The Roxbury Tavern and a visit to Portage with other dates still being booked.&nbsp; We are hard at work on a new CD that will have some original instrumentals, classic bluegrass and of course SpareTime's versions of tunes you have heard before.&nbsp; We are pleased to include Lisa Case-Doro on the CD and in the SpareTime line-up. Having Lisa &amp; Lorie in the band has lowered the average age and improved the appearance of the band.</p>
<p>We are still "havin' a good time".&nbsp; Stop by and see us when you can.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Winter 2012-13</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=winter-2012-13</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=winter-2012-13</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>We are waiting on Spring sometime in June. We made it to Roxbury for "Geezers New Years Eve" &amp; the United Way Benefit at the Barrymore in Feb. (best attendance ever). Now we wait……</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Summer 2012</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=summer-2012</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=summer-2012</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>SpareTime is prepping for a busy summer. So busy, we will be taking off the 3rd Thursdays at the Frequency till August. So stop by on May 17th for our last Frequency appearance until the end of the summer. See you there or see us at the Capital Brewery, Memorial Union Terrace, Whole Foods or the Tyranena Brewery this summer.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>See us on the YouTube</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=see-us-on-the-youtube</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=see-us-on-the-youtube</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/A3eU5FBkis8?si=2265I4YyJSdIK2vq" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/sparetimebluegrass">Watch all the videos on THE TUBE!</a></p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Fall 2011</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=fall-2011</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=fall-2011</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>SpareTime has a guest fiddler. Lisa Case Doro will be singing and playing with the boys (&amp; Lorie). Lisa is from Evansville, Indiana, where she was a Suzuki violin student. She has been a member of various orchestras there and in her subsequent travels. She moved to Nashville and worked as an engineer at the Saturn Car Company. Her coworkers had a band and needed a fiddle player. So she learned some Bluegrass and country music on the fiddle. While in Nashville she worked with up and coming singer songwriter Jamie Spencer in various venues. A move to Ann Arbor brought her into the group Bill Bynum &amp; Co. Bynum, a superb songwriter/performer, gave her an opportunity to plumb bluegrass, folk, and alt country. It also showcased her vocal talent. Now she's in Madison and returning to music after raising her daughter to a pre-school age. It's SpareTime's luck that she's joining with us to bring new harmonies, and a bit of Alison Krauss and Kenny Baker. Come hear and meet her with us at Boo Grass at the High Noon Saloon on Oct 29th or at the Roxbury Tavern on Oct 30th.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Spring/Summer 2011</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=springsummer-2011</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=springsummer-2011</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>SpareTime has been involved with a couple of events linked to the recent and continuing political fight at the Capitol in Madison.&nbsp; We were involved in the "Pickers Local 608" YouTube rendition of "There is Power in the Union".&nbsp; This featured a large group of local players at Audio for the Arts studio playing in support of union rights.</p>
<p>We also performed on April 3rd at the Barrymore for the Forward Wisconsin Fest put on by the Stagehands IATSE local 251. &nbsp;It was a diverse day of music and fun that also signaled our support for good and sane government in Wisconsin.</p>
<p>On a lighter note---SpareTime is going "Up Nort" with a swing through the Upper Penninsula and Northern Wisconsin in June.&nbsp; On June 23rd we will be in Iron Mountain, Michigan for their Off the Square series of concerts.&nbsp; The performance will be downtown and start at 11:30 a.m.&nbsp; We have been there four times and always have a great time.</p>
<p>On June 24th we will be a few miles down the road in Florence, Wisconsin for an evening performance.&nbsp; This is the second time we have played there and the performance starts in the evening on the main road.</p>
<p>Saturday June 25th we will play at the revived Flatrock Bluegrass Festival, this year held at Thorntons Resort &amp; Rafting Company in Crivitz, Wisconsin.&nbsp; We've lost count of our number of appearances at the festival.&nbsp; We always love the audience.&nbsp; It gives us a chance to hook up with old friends, in a friendly locale.</p>
<p>We have been and will continue to play at the Frequency (121 W. Main St. Madison) from 6 to 8 p.m. every 3rd Thursday of the month.&nbsp; As part of the gig we try to feature great local talent during our break.&nbsp; We have shared the stage with "Off the Porch" a trio of fine women singers (they definitely have voice).&nbsp; April will see the Northern Pikers String Band bring their bluegrass to the stage.&nbsp; May brings talent originally from Michigan.&nbsp; Bill Bynum &amp; Company will perform.</p>
<p>The Frequency is definitely a great place to see music.&nbsp; The sound is good.&nbsp; The concert is early enough on a work night.&nbsp; We love playing there.</p>
<p>A word about the Madison Area Music Awards (MAMA).&nbsp; We have won awards and 2007 and 2008.&nbsp; This year we are in the final rounds in three categories---Best County/Bluegrass CD of the year, Best Ensemble Vocals, and Cover Song (for our version of George Harrison's "If I Needed Someone").&nbsp; The nominations are due to our "Someone to Love" CD, released earlier this year.</p>
<p>You can visit the Madison Area Music Association at&nbsp;&nbsp; themamas.org&nbsp; for information on the MAMA and how to vote.&nbsp; Any money generated goes to the purchase and placement of musical instruments into the schools and the hands of school children.&nbsp; The whole thing gives the local music scene and opportunity to keep the music going and getting young people involved.</p>
<p>See you down the road.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>United Way Concert 2011</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=united-way-concert-2011</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=united-way-concert-2011</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>UnitedWayBluegrass11The SpareTime Bluegrass Band is proud to announce its participation in the 10th Annual United Way Bluegrass Concert. The Event, held at the Barrymore, will take place at 1:00 p.m. on February 13th. Since the initial concert, SpareTime has had the pleasure of inviting other area groups and individuals to be part of the music and join in the benefit concert that benefits the local efforts of United Way in assisting area residents. This year the lineup includes Dave Landau with his popular show for children at 1:00 p.m. Dave is a consistent winner in the Best of Madison for Children's Entertainer, but, more than that, a consistent favorite with youngsters. The Cork 'n Bottle String Band is also on the bill. The Corks have been Madison bluegrass favorite for decades. Their tenure at Ken's Bar, the Memorial Union, and other venues has led to the formation of a loyal band of Corkheads eager to listen and watch the Cork 'n Bottle in action. Think of solid musicianship and great tunes. If you ever wondered what a bluegrass Marx Brothers band would be like, come to the Barrymore. The Oak Street Ramblers are again a group taking a part in the concert. the Ramblers have been a mainstay at the Alchemy and the Malt House for several years. This is a relatively young bluegrass band, but one that has been gaining in popularity for some time. Prepare yourself for beautiful harmonies and solid instrumentals. The group is currently mixing its first album. Come out and get a preview of the songs. SpareTime Bluegrass Band has been involved in all ten concerts. The two-time Madison Area Music Award winners have hosted the event. The group is equally adept at traditional bluegrass and material and sources as diverse as the Beatles, George Jones, and Blind Faith. The cost of the kid friendly concert is $10.00 for adults, $5.00 for children over five years of age. Children under five are free. The cost for a family is $20.00 (or the above cost, whichever is lower). The Barrymore Theater always had great snacks and beverages, and has welcomed this concert with open arms. Come out for an afternoon of fun.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>What we did this summer!!</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=what-we-did-this-summer</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=what-we-did-this-summer</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>What we did this summer!! In May the new SpareTime album, "Someone to Love" was released. It veered back to more bluegrass than the last CD’s, but did include a George Harrison tune "If I Needed Someone". Bobby managed to get a picture of his grandparents on the front of the CD. We staged the CD release at the Roxbury Tavern and managed to have some members of Monroe Crossing in the audience. They had done a show nearly next door at the Dorf House, and for an afternoon, Roxbury was the epicenter of the bluegrass world in Wisconsin. The CD was well received there and elsewhere and we thank those who purchased it or listened to us do the whole thing (all the words and all the chords in place) in Roxbury. Brooklyn Fest was in June. We were very honored to play, had a great time, and heard some great music. The festival is in a great venue and the area residents are welcoming and open. We really hope this builds and builds. Our part of the show was recorded and broadcast on WI Public Radio’s Simply Folk on Dec. 5th. The Southern Wisconsin Bluegrass Association asked us to play at the Edgerton Thresheree in September. We had never seen one of these. There was a flea market and a parade of older farm machinery (including some steam powered machines). Everything looked really large, sounded really loud, and seemed really dangerous. If farmers needed to use these machines to grow crops, I hope they got every penny they deserved when they sold the harvest. Weddings were a high spot in the SpareTime recent memory. We played the Tyranena Brewery and had two couples in the audience whose wedding we had played for the year before. It was great to see this marriage thing is not just a passing and everyone was still married. One of the weddings was the first time we had done "If I Needed Someone", which we did at the brewery. The other featured a rendition of "The Proudest Monkey", a Dave Matthews song that we didn't do. We did another wedding in the fall where another Beatles' tune, "In My Life", was tapped for the processional. That wedding was at the Badger Farms, a beautiful converted barn on a working farm in Dane County. The highlight of songs-brides-and-grooms-wanted-us-to-play-at-their-wedding was at our first Jewish wedding. The couple asked for "Deep Elem Blues", a song about an "adult entertainment" area in 1880's Dallas. They also wanted a Beatles' tune "Two of Us" (off the "Let it Be" album). We did those---but they also wanted Hava Nagila. Never having played a Jewish folksong, we had to go back to the chords and crank out a reputable version of the tune. Luckily Paul Kienitz was playing fiddle with us and we came up with a version that sounded a bit Kletzmer and a bit bluegrass. This extended Kletz-Grass dance version of Hava Nagila was the basis for clapping, singing, and the traditional ride by the bride and groom on chairs held high. We were very pleased to be a part of it all. In the coming months SpareTime has several things on tap. We will be doing the traditional "Geezers New Years" at the Roxbury Tavern. This event has become a Wisconsin tradition, albeit and odd one. We play from 7 to 9 in the evening and the Tavern closes at 10. It's Midnight somewhere. This year the event is also a benefit. For information about tickets please contact the Roxbury Tavern. February 13, 2011 will be our annual Bluegrass Benefit for the United Way. This is the 10th anniversary and we are happy to have been a part of it all from the beginning. The usual suspects will be there (Cork and Bottle, Oak Street Ramblers, and special guests). We hope you will be with us. SpareTime is looking forward to the Madison Area Music Awards (MAMAs) in the spring. The album has been nominated for country CD of the year. Remember the Chicago election mantra---vote early and often. Thanks to all of you for your continued support. We hope to see you in the future……</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>New CD - Somone to Love</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=new-cd-somone-to-love</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=new-cd-somone-to-love</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/Sparetime_cover_0510.jpg" alt="image" /></p>
<p>It is almost here!!! The newest SpareTime CD "Someone to Love" will be released on May 23rd. Join us that Sunday at the Roxbury Tavern from 5 till 7 for our CD Release Party. All of our CD's will be available for the rare price of 2 for $10. We recorded most of the CD live at the United Way benefit at the Barrymore Theater with some additional selections from our show at the Frequency. Come by and help celebrate 16 years of SpareTime and our newest project.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>United Way Concert</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=united-way-concert</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=united-way-concert</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/UnitedWayBluegrassPoster2010web-790x1024.jpg" alt="image" /></p>
<p>Hello All, SpareTime is proud to announce the 9th Annual United Way Bluegrass Concert. The event is on Sunday, February 14th at the Barrymore, starting at 1:00 p.m. We've been lucky enough to have been involved in this event since its inception. We've invited other bands to share the stage and bring out the bluegrass community in an effort to assist the United Way in bringing its many services to the community. This year the family friendly event features Dave Laundau, Cork 'N Bottle String Band, The Oak Street Rambler, and SpareTime. The ticket prices remain unchanged at $10 for adults, $5 for children, or $20 for families. The concert is a great afternoon of local bluegrass and a fun way to spend a Sunday afternoon. We hope to see you there.</p>
<p>~ <em>SpareTime Bluegrass Band</em></p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>SpareTime Holiday CD</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-holiday-cd</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-holiday-cd</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Hi All,</p>
<p>We had a great time at the Roxbury Tavern on Dec. 6th and played a surprise gig at the Frequency in Madison on Dec. 17th.&nbsp; Our X mas songs were a big hit and Lorie thinks we should do a holiday CD.&nbsp; So we need some holiday songs you’d like to hear done by SpareTime.</p>
<p>We have 3 songs so far:</p>
<ul>
<li>Please, Daddy don’t get drunk this Christmas</li>
<li>Angels we have heard on high (instrumental)</li>
<li>Merry X-mas from the Family</li>
</ul>
<p>What holiday songs would you like?&nbsp; Add your comments below and we hope to have a CD ready for the Holidays 2010.</p>
<p>Thanks…..SpareTime Bluegrass</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Where to be on Dec. 6th!</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-bluegrass</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-bluegrass</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/dessertpartydec6.jpg" alt="image" /></p>
<p>No Packer game on Sunday, so head out to Roxbury.</p>
<p>Sam's Music Club is presenting a benefit for the Northwest Dane Senior Center featuring, in order of appearance, Lisa's Lovely Desserts and the SpareTime Bluegrass Band.</p>
<p><a href="roxburytavern.com">Roxbury Tavern</a> December 6, 3:00-6:00 pm. $10 at the door.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>SpareTime Wins MAMA</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-wins-mama</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-wins-mama</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/mama.png" alt="image" /></p>
<p>SpareTime Bluegrass is proud to announce that its latest CD, "Bluegrass Matinee," won Best Country/Bluegrass Album of the Year at the <a href="http://themamas.org/">Madison Area Music Awards</a> (MAMA) in its fourth annual awards ceremony held at the Barrymore Theatre in Madison, WI on May 12, 2007.</p>
<p>The MAMAs recognizes local music and musicians of all genres, at the same time raising money for the purchase of musical instruments for young people and promoting music in the schools. SpareTime is happy to be recognized by the MAMAs and be a part of their laudable efforts.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>6th Annual United Way Bluegrass Show</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=6th-annual-united-way-bluegrass-show</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=6th-annual-united-way-bluegrass-show</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="assets/images/6th.united.way_.show_.jpg" alt="image" /></p>
<p>The SpareTime Bluegrass Band is headlining the 6th annual United Way benefit concert on Sunday, February 11th. During the afternoon, they will be turning the stage over to the always energetic Lonesome Rogues, and the perrenial masters of entertainment and surprise, The Cork ‘n’ Bottle String Band.</p>
<p>The attached PDF poster gives the details about time, price and the Barrymore’s address, so don’t miss this chance to lend support to those in our community who could use a helping hand. It’s a great way to spend a cold Sunday getting a warm feeling and sharing the day with our great and generous local bluegrass musicians.</p>
<p>Hope to see y’all there.</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Steeno's Gone - SpareTime Continues</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=steenos-gone-sparetime-continues</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=steenos-gone-sparetime-continues</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The Steeno's have now moved to Florida where they are basking in a tropical paradise. To contact them please see the “Contact us” page.</p>
<p>SpareTime continues and welcomes bass player Lorie Docken to the band. She has been the “back-up” bassist for 2 years and takes over the job full-time (well part-time since we are only SpareTime).</p>
<p>Other musician friends are gracing us with their presence on the stage. This adds new songs to the repertoire with different voices and instruments.</p>
<p>The Labor Day weekend gig at the Roxbury Tavern featured Jim and Laura Lotridge and young Dane . Jim and Laura play with Kevin Tubb and the Welldiggers and also with the perennial local bluegrass band, Pat Downings' Down from the Hills.</p>
<p>The September Hody Bar gig featured mandolin and tenor singer Dale Ward . Dale regularly practices and plays with Jefferson County .</p>
<p>The October Hody Bar gig includes Madison bluegrass all-stars George Diak on mandolin and Scott Shank on Dobro. George and Scott have both played with SpareTime before. Having them again adds volumes of songs to the list.</p>
<p>Stay tuned to see who else stops in……</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>No Way!!!!</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=no-way</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=no-way</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Big transformations are happening to the SpareTime bunch as Bob &amp; Lisa Steeno change addresses. Bobby has taken an early retirement and they are moving to a et to be built cottage on Florida's panhandle. The remaining band, Bob Batyko &amp; Jim Robarts, will be using various sit in guests to continue the SpareTime tradition. The Steeno's are already planning the reunion gigs next summer with appearances at Flatrock and the Bluegrass Bash on the agenda.</p>
<p>A good-bye Steeno gig is planned for the breakfast brunch at the Eldorado on Sunday Sept. 12 th . The Steeno's and friends will perform. Then we'll wave good-bye (ie Dorothy and the wizard leaving for Kansas) as the Steeno van and pop-up leave Wisconsin for the start of retirement in Florida.</p>
<p>Remember Steeno's, there's no place like home….. So the road goes on forever and SpareTime never ends….</p>]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <title>Sparetime Bluegrass - Who Are These Guys?</title>
    <link>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-bluegrass-who-are-these-guys</link>
    <guid>https://qualityshepherd.github.io/sparetimebluegrass/#post?s=sparetime-bluegrass-who-are-these-guys</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The SpareTime Bluegrass Band 2004</p>
<p>The name is indicative of both the state of bluegrass music and the fact that everyone has an actual job. Years ago the Country Gazette released an album titled "Don't give Up Your Day Job"-a joshing reminder to bluegrass artists of where there priorities might lay. SpareTime, no fools, took the advice to heart and dedicated themselves to having Bluegrass fun in their "Spare Time."</p>
<p>"Ten years ago on a cold, dark night"…..is a wonderful opening line for a song, and has relevance to The SpareTime Bluegrass Band as an indicator of how much time has passed for the band. It was some ten years ago (the origins are hazy-indicating much beer under the bridge) that SpareTime was formed by Dave Carper, Steve "Buck "Bethel, Bob Batyko, and Bobby Steeno. Over the years other musicians have cycled through the group, most notably Sims Delaney-Potthoff, Jennifer Little, and Scott R. Shank. Other musicians were "Spare Parts" for the band-a loose mélange of players brought in on special occasions. George Diak, Lorie Docken, and Mike Schmidt spared their time to be with the band.</p>
<p>Today the core lineup is: Bob Batyko: guitar, Bobby Steeno: mandolin, Lisa Steeno: bass, and Jim Robarts: banjo. The last year has seen Rebecca Patek on fiddle for various dates.</p>
<p>The band is thoroughly grounded in "traditional" bluegrass and performs numbers from Monroe, Flatt &amp; Scruggs, the Stanley Brothers, and Jimmy Martin. SpareTime also dips into numbers by Robbie Fulks, the Rolling Stones, Blind Faith, and Bob Dylan (with occasional forays in John Hartford and polka music). In short the mix is eclectic, but rooted in a bluegrass instrumentation and sensibility.</p>
<p>Given that the bluegrass world is a small, cohesive mix of professional and semi-professional bands, the SpareTime Bluegrass Band has appeared on bills with Del McCoury, James King, Special Consensus, David Davis &amp; the Warrior River Boys, and Lynne Morris. Of course SpareTime has played its share of weddings, bars, church bazaars, water parks, and birthday parties. Once they even backed up an older gentleman on musical saw (mercifully for only one song and suffering the criticisms of the saw "artist" when they didn't seem to pick up the musical key quickly enough). In the words of the Grateful Dead, "What a long strange trip it's been."</p>
<p>On the personal front everyone has a college education, everyone has adult children no longer living at home. Everyone has a job. Everyone (amazingly) has a full head of hair. On the individual, personal front……..</p>]]></description>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>